# **CECIL E. KING**

1268 Foxglove Place, Mississauga, ON, L5V2N3 Email: cek333@yahoo.com | Phone: 647-238-4395

Portfolio: https://cek333.github.io/Responsive Portfolio/portfolio.html

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/cecil-e-king/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/cecil-e-king/</a> | Github: <a href="https://github.com/cek333">https://github.com/cek333</a>

## **SUMMARY**

I'm a full stack web developer with a background in ASIC verification. In Dec 2020, I obtained a certificate in web development from the UofT SCS Coding bootcamp. At the bootcamp, I worked individually and in teams to construct applications utilizing the full MERN stack (MongoDB/Mongoose, Express, React, and Node.js). As a verification engineer, I developed tests, troubleshooted failures, and collaborated with globally dispersed team members, thereby sharpening my debugging and written communication skills. I'm also detailed-oriented, a quick learner, and I relish the opportunity to solve problems with creative solutions.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Languages:** Javascript, jQuery, C, Perl, SystemVerilog **Databases:** MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, React

**Backend:** Node.js, Express, Handlebars, REST APIs

Version Control: Git, Github, CVS, Mercurial

**Deployment**: Heroku

### **PROJECTS**

**Reading List:** Full stack app to search for and save books of interest.

- Github: https://github.com/cek333/Reading List
- Deployed: https://reading-list-45753.herokuapp.com/
- Technologies Used: MERN (MongoDB/Mongoose, Express, React, Node.js), Bootstrap

Eat-Da-Burger: Full stack app to add and update lists of burgers.

- Github: <a href="https://github.com/cek333/Eat-Da-Burger">https://github.com/cek333/Eat-Da-Burger</a>
- Deployed: https://radiant-basin-63106.herokuapp.com/
- Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express, Handlebars, MySQL

### **E-logical Trivia:** Trivia Quiz App. Bootcamp group project.

- Github: https://github.com/FarhinChowdhury/Trivia-Quiz
- Deployed: <a href="https://e-logical-trivia-20809.herokuapp.com/">https://e-logical-trivia-20809.herokuapp.com/</a>
- Technologies Used: MERN (MongoDB/Mongoose, Express, React, Node.js), Bootstrap

### **EXPERIENCE**

**Senior Engineer, Hardware:** Pixelworks, Toronto, Ontario (Aug 2017 - Aug 2020)

- Generated clean regression reports pre-tapeout with over 95% branch and statement coverage by:
  - Running the IP and full-chip simulations and generating the regression and coverage reports
  - Notifying the IP designers of any issues and verifying the fixes
  - Writing test plans and tests, and maintaining testbenches for IPs in the Iris product line using the object-oriented Universal Verification Methodology (UVM)
- Supported successful functional and performance verification on the prototyping systems by partitioning the RTL design across multiple FPGAs using Synopsys' Certify

Senior Engineer, HW Emulation: Vixs Systems, Toronto, Ontario (Nov 2010 - Aug 2017) Engineer, ASIC Engineering, HW Emulation: Vixs Systems (Jul 2007 - Nov 2010) System Verification Engineer: Vixs Systems (May 2004 - Jul 2007)

- Worked on the verification of the company's ASIC designs, enabling first-pass silicon success on tapeout by:
  - Maintaining in-house and third-party FPGA prototyping systems used for the verification of XCode products
  - Partitioning the RTL design across multiple FPGAs using in-house and third-party tools
  - Developing and maintaining synthesis and place and route scripts that transformed the RTL into programmable bitfiles for testing on the prototyping systems
  - Debugging and resolving place and route issues
  - Writing tests for some of the XCode IPs (Transport Stream Demux, Smartcard)
  - Assisting with the maintenance of the full verification test suite
  - Troubleshooting regression failures
- Contributed to the successful launch of many of our customers' products by assisting the Field Application Engineers with debugging product issues

### **EDUCATION**

**Bootcamp Certificate:** University of Toronto School of Continuing Studies (Sep - Dec 2020)

 Three month ramp up on the technologies and skills necessary for full stack web development

**Certificate, Computer Security and Digital Forensics:** Ryerson University - G. Raymond Chang School of Continuing Education (2014 - 2017)

• Program Covered: Computer Network Security, Cryptography, Digital Forensics Systems, Security Architecture and Design, CISSP (Prep), and a Capstone Project

**Bachelor of Applied Science, Computer Engineering:** University of Toronto (1999 - 2004)